(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-10T23:47:01.011802",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Fire away! Leave behind the dreams engraved in your heart
未来さえ置き去りにして
Leaving even the future behind
限界など知らない 意味無い！
Knowing no limits, they're meaningless!
この能力が光散らす
This power scatters the light
散らす
...radiate.
その先に遥かな想いを
Radiating these distant feelings into the future...
歩いてきたこの道を
On this path I've walked,
振り返ることしか
if the only thing I can do
出来ないなら...
is look back...
今ここで全てを壊せる
I can destroy everything right here and now.
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
The cityscape descends into darkness.
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
How far can people stand and fight?
加速するその痛みから
From this accelerating pain,
誰かをきっと守れるよ
I'm sure I can protect someone.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Looking! I'll blitz loop this planet to search for a way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it.
今すぐ 身体中を 光の速さで
Right now, running through my body at the speed of light,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
is a definite premonition.
掴め！望むものなら残さず
Grab it! Leave nothing behind if it's what you desire,
輝ける自分らしさで
with a shining individuality.
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow made that day.
この瞳に光る涙
Even the tears shining in these eyes
それさえも強さになるから
will turn into my strength!
立ち止まると 少しだけ
When I stop, just a little bit,
感じる切なさに
at the painful sadness I feel,
戸惑う事無いなんて
I won't lie and say
嘘はつかないよ
that I'm never confused.
宙に舞うコインが描く
The parabolic arc drawn by a coin flipped in the air
放物線が決める運命
will decide our fate.
打ち出した答えが今日も
The answer shot forth rushes through
私の胸を駆け巡る
my chest again today.
Sparkling! The shiny lights awake true desire.
Sparkling! The shiny lights awaken true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it.
必ず 貫いてく 途惑うことなく
I'll pierce through without fail, without hesitation.
傷ついても 走り続ける
Even if I get hurt, I'll keep running!
狙え！凛と煌めく視線は
Take aim! The cold, glittering gaze
狂い無く闇を切り裂く
tears through the darkness without straying.
迷いなんて 吹き飛ばせばいい
Just blow away all hesitation.
この心が叫ぶ限り
As long as my heart cries out,
誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
I won't let anyone get in my way!
儚く舞う無数の願いは
Countless fleetingly dancing wishes
この両手に積もっていく
gather in both of my hands.
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは
What comes into view through the piercing darkness
重く深く切ない記憶
are heavy, deep, and painful memories.
色褪せてく現実に揺れる
Trembling in a fading reality,
絶望には負けたくない
I don't want to lose to despair.
私があれ私であること
Being who I am right now,
胸を張って全て誇れる！
I can hold my head high and be proud of it all!
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Looking! I'll blitz loop this planet to search for a way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it.
今すぐ 身体中を 光の速さで
Right now, running through my body at the speed of light,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
is a definite premonition.
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Fire away! The dreams engraved in your heart,
未来さえ置き去りにして
leaving even the future behind!
限界など知らない 意味無い！
Knowing no limits—it's meaningless!
この能力が光散らす
This power radiates light...
その先に遥かな想いを
sending distant feelings far beyond!
突然降る夕立
A sudden evening downpour...
あぁ 傘もないや 嫌
Ah, I don't even have an umbrella, I hate this!
空のご機嫌なんか知らない
I don't care about the mood of the sky.
季節の変わり目の服は
What am I supposed to wear
何着りゃいいんだろ
when the seasons change?
春と秋どこいっちゃったんだよ
Where did spring and autumn go?
息も出来ない
I can't even breathe...
情報の圧力
overwhelmed by information.
めまいの螺旋だ
It's a spiral of dizziness.
わたしはどこにいる
Where am I?
こんなに こんなに
Even though my breathing
息の音がするのに
sounds so loud, so loud...
変だね 世界の音がしない
It's strange, I can't hear the sound of the world.
しない 足りない 足りない
Not enough, not enough,
誰にも気づかれない
no one notices me.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed while unable to make even a rough scribble of a sound.
「ありのまま」なんて 誰に見せるんだ
"Just as I am"—who am I supposed to show that to?
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
So a fool like me can only sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Shall I blurt it all out to the stars!
エリクサーに張り替える作業も なんとなくなんだ
Changing to Elixir strings felt kind of aimless too.
欠けた爪を少し触る
Caress my chipped fingernail a bit.
半径300mmの体で 必死に鳴いてる
Desperately crying out with a body radius of 300 mm.
音楽にとっちゃ ココが地球だな
For music, this right here is Earth.
空気を握って 空を殴るよ
Clench the air and punch the sky.
なんにも起きない わたしは無力さ
Nothing happened, I was helpless.
だけどさ その手で この鉄を弾いたら
But if I pluck this steel string with that hand,
何かが変わって見えた...ような。
I felt like something changed... it seemed like.
眩しい 眩しい そんなに光るなよ
So bright, so bright, don't shine so dazzlingly.
わたしのダサい影が より色濃くなってしまうだろう
My lame shadow will only grow even darker.
なんでこんな熱くなっちゃってんだ 止まんない
Why did I get so fired up? It won't stop!
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
So a fool like me can only sing.
うるさいんだって 心臓
Shut up, heart!
蒼い惑星 ひとりぼっち いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
Alone on a blue planet, I've listened to so many sounds.
回り続けて 幾億年 一瞬でもいいから...あぁ
It keeps spinning for hundreds of millions of years, even for a moment... ah.
聴いて 聴けよ
Hear it, listen to me.
わたし わたし わたしはここにいる
I, I, I am right here!
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed while unable to make even a rough scribble of a sound.
なんかになりたい なりたい 何者かでいい
I want to become something, I want to be someone, anyone!
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
So a fool like me can only sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Shall I blurt it all out to the stars!
歌聴いてくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for listening to my song!
聴いてくれるこの環境、とっても嬉しく思いま...
Having this environment where everyone listens to me makes me so happy...
いやぁ、おさらいするのもね、もうかなり難しくて、練習頑張ったんで、どうだったかな？
Man, even practicing it was pretty tough, but I worked really hard on it! How was it?
よかったー！嬉しいー！
Thank goodness! I'm so happy!
あっ、ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためでーす！
Ah, I'm Tsunomaki Watame from Hololive 4th Generation!
これみよがしに弾いていまーす！今日でなんと！9歳になりましたー！
I'm showing off my playing! And today, I turned 9 years old!
いやお祝いいっぱい、ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all the birthday wishes! Thank you so much!
いや、この日のために、もうたくさんたくさん頑張って準備もしてきたので、ぜひ最後まで見て楽しんでほしいなと思います！
I worked really, really hard preparing for this day, so I hope you'll watch and enjoy until the very end!
よろしくベイベー！
Nice to meet you, baby!
ということでね、これは片付けますね。もう使わないのでね。
So with that, I'll put this away now. I won't be using it anymore.
はい、ちょっと待っててね。よいしょ、よいしょ。このギターが...ふぅ...オッケー！
Okay, please wait a sec. Ups-a-daisy. Ups-a-daisy. This guitar... phew... Okay!
ふぅー、肩こりになっちまう。よいしょ。
Phew, my shoulders are getting stiff. There we go.
いや、待っててくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for waiting!
今日のハッシュタグはなんと前代未聞！
Today's hashtag is truly unprecedented!
こちら、「角巻わため生誕祭2025」なので、こちらのハッシュタグをつけて、たくさんポストしていただけると嬉しいです！
It's "Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Festival 2025", so I'd be so happy if you posted a lot with this hashtag!
今日はアニソンNight Fever! 楽しんでいけますかー？！
Today is Anison Night Fever! Are you ready to have fun?!
いけますかー？！
Are you ready?!
わためは、いけますー！
Watame is ready!
では、アニソンNight Fever! 行くぞー！
Then, Anison Night Fever! Let's go!
ん？
Huh?
なんだこれはい？
What is this?
こんなのステージに置いてあったらいけないでしょ！
You can't just leave something like this on stage!
つぎにー！
Next...
何これ？
What is this?
ん？何なの？誰こんなん置いたの？ん？
Huh? What is it? Who left this here? Huh?
なんじゃこりゃー！
What on earth is this?!
このままもう少し歩こう 肩を抱き
Let's walk a little further like this, shoulder to shoulder,
消えゆく夢を数え 枯れてく仲間を見た
counting fading dreams, watching friends wither away.
通い慣れた道に迷い込む このごろ
Lately, I've been getting lost on familiar roads,
闇がもう一人の自分をつくる
and the darkness creates another version of myself.
渇いた叫びが くじけそうな胸を突き刺す
A thirsty cry pierces my heart that feels ready to break.
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you along to see the world.
だれにも出せない答えが僕の中にある
Inside of me lies an answer that no one else can reach.
駆け引きがカギ
Haggling strategy is the key,
とどけ fly at higher game
reach out and fly at a higher game.
いくつの悲しみを一緒に越えただろう？
How many sorrows have we overcome together?
気が済むまで求めたあの日の僕達がいた
Back then, we sought answers until our hearts were satisfied.
時代が巡るなら またどこかで会えるね
If time comes full circle, we'll meet again somewhere.
その時が来るまで 諦めない
Until that moment comes, I won't give up.
冷めてく想いは どうしても否めないけど
Though I can't deny that my feelings are cooling down,
恋に落ちて変わってくのもいいね
falling in love and changing isn't so bad either.
焦らず 騒がず あるがままでと願うから
Without rushing or panicking, I pray for things to be as they are,
心に話を
so with flowers in our hearts,
咲かそう just take my heart
let's make them bloom, just take my heart.
渇いた叫びが くじけそうな胸を突き刺す
A thirsty cry pierces my heart that feels ready to break.
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you along to see the world.
だれにも出せない答えが夢の中にある
Inside a dream lies an answer that no one else can reach.
僕を信じて
Believe in me,
咲かそう just take my heart
let's make them bloom, just take my heart,
人生は続いてく
for life keeps going on.
明日へ続く坂道の途中で
On the way up the slope leading to tomorrow,
すれ違う大人たちはつぶやくのさ
the adults passing by murmur:
「愛とか夢とか理想も分かるけど
"I understand about love, dreams, and ideals,
目の前の現実そんなに甘くない」って
but reality right now isn't that sweet."
つまづきながらも 転がりながらも
Stumbling along, rolling along,
カサブタだらけの情熱を忘れたくない
I don't want to forget a passion full of scabs.
大人になれない僕らの
Listen to one of our bluffs,
強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
we who cannot become adults.
逃げも隠れもしないから
We won't run or hide,
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
so let those who want to laugh, laugh.
せめて頼りない僕らの
At least don't pluck away
自由の芽を摘み取らないで
the fragile buds of our freedom.
水をあげるその役目を
Isn't it enough to fulfill
果たせばいいんだろう？
our role of watering them?
何度も繰り返した失敗とか
With all the repeated failures
大きく食い違った考えとか
and greatly differing thoughts,
僕らの基準はとても不確かで
Our standards are very uncertain,
昨日よりなんとなく歩幅が広くなった
yet our stride felt somehow wider than yesterday.
背伸びをしながら 打ちのめされながら
Stretching up, getting beaten down,
カサブタをちょっとはがすけど 答えは出ない
I peel off the scab a little, but no answer comes out.
大人になりたい僕らの
Listen to one of our selfish requests,
わがままをひとつ聞いてくれ
we who want to become adults.
寝ても覚めても縛られる
Stop time just a little bit,
時間を少しだけ止めて
which binds us whether asleep or awake.
せめてふがいない僕らの
At least don't cut away
自由の実を切り取らないで
our free bodies, pathetic as we are.
赤く熟すその時まで
Shouldn't we worry
悩めばいいんだろう？
until the moment it ripens red?
大人になれない僕らの
Listen to one of our bluffs,
強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
we who cannot become adults.
逃げも隠れもしないから
We won't run or hide,
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
so let those who want to laugh, laugh.
せめて頼りない僕らの
At least don't pluck away
自由の芽を摘み取らないで
the fragile buds of our freedom.
水をあげるその役目を
Isn't it enough to fulfill
果たせばいいんだろう？
our role of watering them?
会いたいな
I want to meet you,
会えないな
I can't meet you,
切ないな
it's so painful,
この気持ち
this feeling.
言えないの
I can't say it,
言いたいの
I want to say it,
チャンス逃してばかり
always missing my chance.
だって だって
Because, because,
翼広げ二人で
spreading our wings together,
空をマラソン
running a marathon in the sky,
夢をユニゾンしたい
I want to harmonize our dreams.
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me
Look! Catch You, Catch You, Catch Me, Catch Me!
待って
Wait,
こっちを向いて
look over here
スキだと言って
and say you love me!
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You
Yes, Nice to Meet You, Good to See You!
きっと 私の想い
Surely, my feelings...
あなたのハートに
...will fly straight into your heart!
飛んで 飛んで 飛んでいけ
Fly, fly, fly to you!
迷わない
I won't hesitate!
たまにね なくなっちゃう
Sometimes, the battery in my body
身体のバッテリー
runs out...
あなたの笑顔で
With your smile,
いつも充電満タン パワー爆発しちゃえ
I'm fully charged, ready to explode with power!
パワー爆発しちゃえ
Explode with power!
お願い
Please,
please,
まずは お友達から
starting off as friends,
笑って 見つめて 楽しい
smiling and staring at each other, I want to make
毎日 にしたい
every day fun!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me, absolutely!
運命だって お似合いだって そう
Because it's fate, because we're a perfect match, yes!
Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Nice to meet you, good to see you, for sure!
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で 一番 一番 一番 一番
I won't lose to anyone, in this world you're my number one, number one, number one, number one!
コ・イ・シ・テ・ル
I'm – in – love – with – you!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
Look, catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me, wait up!
こっちをむいて スキだといって そう
Look at me and tell me you love me, yes!
Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Nice to meet you, good to see you, for sure!
私の想い あなたのハートに 飛んで 飛んで 飛んで 飛んでいけ
My feelings will fly, fly, fly, fly into your heart!
迷わない
They won't go astray!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me, absolutely!
運命だって お似合いだって そう
Because it's fate, because we're a perfect match, yes!
Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Nice to meet you, good to see you, for sure!
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で 一番 一番 一番 一番
I won't lose to anyone, in this world you're my number one, number one, number one, number one!
コ・イ・シ・テ・ル
I'm – in – love – with – you!
また夢から覚める、濡れた瞼を開ける
Waking from another dream, opening wet eyelids
狂おしいほど思い残す、遠い日の無力さを呪う
Leaving behind agonizing regrets, cursing the powerlessness of distant days
身を焼かれるような絶望も糧にはなろうか
Can despair that burns the body become nourishment?
憧れに焦がれるまま燃やし続けている
Continuing to burn while consumed by longing
キラキラお星様宿したあなたのeyes
Your eyes with sparkling little stars
カラカラ渇いて可哀想なlack of 愛?
Dry and parched, a pitiful lack of love?
全てを孤独から救う眩しい光
Dazzling light saving everything from loneliness
僕にだけ落ちる影はあなたのせい?
Is the shadow falling only on me your fault?
致命的な欠落をくれたね
You gave me a fatal flaw
身勝手な巨星、狂わされた生
A selfish giant, a life driven mad
お願い、声を聞かせて、声を聞かせて
Please, let me hear your voice, let me hear your voice
絡まって歪んでしまった傷さえ
Even the wounds that became entangled and distorted
くれたのはあなただけ、あなただけ
You were the only one who gave them to me, only you
お願い、僕を見ていて、僕を見ていて
Please, look at me, look at me
宿命に刻まれた痛みさえ武器にして
Using even the pain carved into destiny as a weapon
いつかの後悔すら照らせるように
So that even regrets of the past can be illuminated
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I cannot live without you
何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
It's fine even if I sacrifice everything
あなたの愛がまだ足らない
Your love is still not enough
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい?
What should I use to fill the empty space?
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love
運命的、運命的、運命的な I
Fateful, fateful, fateful "I"
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow
僕を見ていてね、最愛のファタール!
Please look at me, my dearest Fatal!
キラキラお星様宿したあなたのeyes
Your eyes with sparkling little stars
カラカラ渇いて可哀想なlack of 愛?
Dry and parched, a pitiful lack of love?
遥か彼方から放たれた美しさに
To the beauty released from far away
灼かれた眼、もがれた羽根、創造的堕天
Burnt eyes, plucked feathers, creative fall from grace
あらゆる視界をジャック その輝きはエゴイスティック
Jack every field of vision, that brilliance is egoistic
胸の奥仕舞い込んだ感情すら 引っ張り出して昇華して
Pulling out even the emotions stored deep in the chest and sublimating them
僕という運命を全部抱きしめていく
Embracing all of the destiny called me
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I cannot live without you
眩しさでこの身を照らして欲しい
I want you to illuminate this body with your brilliance
あなたの愛がまだ足らない
Your love is still not enough
夢の中でもらうしかないのに
Even though I can only receive it in dreams
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love
運命的、運命的、運命的な I
Fateful, fateful, fateful "I"
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow
誰のものでもない 最愛のファタール!
Nobody else's, my dearest Fatal!
何度悔やんだだろう 何度呪っただろう
How many times did I regret? How many times did I curse?
どれほどの幸福を注いだとしても
No matter how much happiness is poured,
満たされることのない器
a vessel that is never filled.
何度夢見ただろう 何度願っただろう
How many times did I dream? How many times did I wish?
僕の胸で膿み続けている傷を撫でる手を
The hand stroking the wound continuing to fester in my chest...
撫でる手を
...The hand stroking the wound...
この舞台で足掻くことをやめない
I won't stop struggling on this stage
ただ一つのアイに近づきたい
Wanting to get closer to a single love
固く定まったこの宿命
This firmly established destiny
あの星の光からこぼれた闇
Darkness spilling from the light of that star
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I cannot live without you
何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
It's fine if I offer up everything
あなたの愛がまだ足らない
Your love is still not enough
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい？
What should I use to fill what is missing?
致命的 致命的 致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love
運命的 運命的 運命的な愛
Fated, fated, fated love
必然的 必然的 必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow
僕を見ていてね
Please watch over me
最愛のファタール！
My dearest fatale!
最愛のファタール
My dearest fatale
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
Proof of reaching the end
長過ぎる旅路から
From a journey far too long
切り出した一節
A passage cut out
それはかつてこの地に
That was when once in this land
影を落とした悪を
Over the evil that cast a shadow
打ち取りし勇者との
With the hero who defeated it
短い旅の記憶
Memories of a short journey
物語は終わり
The story comes to an end
勇者は眠りにつく
The hero falls into slumber
穏やかな日常を
Leaving behind a peaceful everyday life
この地に残して
In this land
時の流れは無情に
The flow of time, mercilessly
人を忘れさせる
Makes people forget
そこに生きた軌跡も
Even the traces of life lived there
錆び付いていく
Begin to rust
それでも君の
Even so, your
言葉も願いも勇気も
Words, wishes, and courage
今も確かに私の中で
Are still vividly inside of me
生きている
Living on
同じ途を選んだ
We chose the same path
それだけだったはずなのに
That should have been all it was
いつの間にかどうして
Yet somehow, without knowing why
頬を伝う涙の
The tears streaming down my cheeks
理由をもっと知りたいんだ
I want to know the reason for them more
今更だって
Even if it's late now
共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
If I trace the journey we walked together
そこに君は居なくとも
Even if you are not there
きっと見つけられる
I'm sure I can find it
物語は続く
The story continues
一人の旅へと発つ
Embarking on a solitary journey
立ち寄る街で出会う人の
Of the people encountered in towns visited
記憶の中に残る君は
You remaining in their memories
相も変わらずお人好しで
Are still the same kind-hearted person
格好つけてばかりだね
Always trying to act cool
あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは
The symbols created here and there
勝ち取った平和の証
Are the proof of the peace won
それすら
Even those
未来でいつか
Someday in the future
私がい人にならないように
So that I won't be alone
あの旅を思い出せるように
So that I can remember that journey
残された目印
Markers left behind
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
Proof of reaching the end
私を変えた出会い
The encounter that changed me
百分の一の旅路
One percent of a journey
君の勇気をいつか
Someday, your courage
風がさらって
Carried away by the wind
誰の記憶から消えてしまっても
Even if it fades from everyone's memory
私がい未来に連れて行くから
I will carry it with me into the future
君の手を取った
I took your hand
あの日に全て始まった
And that day everything began
くだらなくて
It was trivial, and
思わずふっと笑ってしまうような
Unintentionally made me chuckle
ありふれた時間が今も眩しい
Those ordinary moments are still radiant now
知りたいんだ
I want to know
今更だって
Even at this late hour
振り返るとそこにはいつでも
Whenever I look back, you're always there
優しく微笑みかける
Smiling gently at me
君がいるから
Because you are there
新たな旅の始まりは
The beginning of a new journey
君が守り抜いたこの地に
In this land you protected
芽吹いた命と共に
Together with the sprouting life
勇者、いい曲だったねー！
"Yuusha" was a great song, wasn't it?
うんー！
Yeah!
VJとかもね、あ、VJっていうのはこの後ろのMVのことなんだけど
The VJ work too—ah, VJ refers to the MV playing behind me—
VJとかもね、こだわって見たので
We put a lot of care into the VJ visuals as well,
ぜひぜひいっぱい見てもらいたいな
so I really hope you'll watch it a lot!
アーカイブとかもね！まだ終わってないけどね！
In the archives too! Though the stream isn't over yet!
ゲストさんもいっぱい来てくれて嬉しいよー！
I'm so happy so many guests came to join me!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
なんかさー
You know...
今までのセトリさ、あの平成の...
Our setlist so far, like, filled with Heisei...
...とか
...or something.
ま、令和のアニソンとかを盛り込んでみたんだけど
Well, I tried to include some Reiwa anime songs,
知ってる曲はありましたか？
did you recognize any of them?
お気に入りの曲とかあったかな〜？
Did you have any favorites?
なんか好きな曲とか、もし見つかったりしたら教えてほしいなと思います。
If you found any songs you liked, I'd love for you to tell me.
この曲良かったよーとか教えてください！
Please let me know if there were any songs you enjoyed!
あ、今コメントで教えてくれてもいいんだよ〜
Ah, you can even tell me in the comments right now~
うんうんうんうん
Mm-hmm, yeah...
でーもー！
But!
これで終わりじゃないんだよね！
This isn't the end yet!
1曲だけ...
Just one song...
ま、この後ちょっとゲームの曲とかもなんか混ざってんだけど
Well, after this, there are even some game songs mixed in,
あの、コンセプトがあるセトリになってます、この後！
but the upcoming setlist has a clear theme!
探してみてもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd love it if you try to figure it out!
ゲストさんもね、まだ出ていない人もいるので
Also, there are still guests who haven't appeared yet,
楽しみにしててくださーい！
so look forward to it!
はーい！
Yay!
よーし
Alright...
では、聴いてください。
Now then, please listen.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
embracing an unyielding wish.
海の色が紅く染まってゆく
The color of the sea turns crimson,
無重力状態
weightless...
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind like this.
いつも跳べないハードルを
I've always cleared unjumpable hurdles
負けない気持ちで
with an undefeatable spirit,
クリアしてきたけど
but...
出し切れな実力は
The potential I couldn't fully unleash,
誰のせい？
whose fault is it?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
embracing an unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図
the unfading map of my heart,
光にかざそう
let me hold it up to the light!
どれだけ泣けば 朝に出会えるの
How much do I have to cry until I meet the morning?
孤独な夜 初めて限界を感じた日
On a lonely night, the day I first felt my limits...
きっと恋に落ちるのは
Surely, falling in love is like a blink,
まばたきみたいな
a passion of a single moment,
一瞬の情熱だけど
but...
愛に続く坂道で
On the slope that leads to love,
強さ覚えたい
I want to learn true strength.
止まらない未来を夢見て
Dreaming of an unstoppable future,
口を閉ざし
I kept my mouth closed
瞳を光らせてきたけれど
and let my eyes shine, but...
もっと大きな優しさが見えた
I was able to see an even greater kindness.
跳べないハードルを
Hurdles I couldn't jump,
負けない気持ちで
with an undefeatable spirit,
クリアしてきたけど
I've cleared them, but...
スタートラインに立つたびに
Every time I stood at the starting line,
怯えていた
I was frightened.
止まらない未来を描いて
Picturing an unstoppable future,
腕を伸ばし
reaching out my arms
心を開いて
and opening my heart...
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
embracing an unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図
the unfading map of my heart,
光にかざそう
let me hold it up to the light!
胸に こみ上げてく
Welling up inside my heart,
熱く 激しい この想い
this burning, intense passion...
僕らは行く 最後の戦場へ
We are heading to the final battlefield.
手を取り合い 誓い合って
Joining hands and swearing to each other,
明日の夜明け前に
before tomorrow's dawn,
あの宇宙へと 旅立つのさ
we will depart into that outer space.
僕らが地球にいたことだけ
Just the fact that we were here on Earth,
どうか 覚えていて欲しいよ
please, I just want you to remember.
振り返るな
Don't look back,
涙を見せるな
don't show your tears!
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
明日を取り戻すんだ
We will take back our tomorrow!
(WO WOH WOH)
GONG 鳴らせ!!
Sound the GONG!!
今こそ 立ち上がれ 運命の戦士よ
Now is the time! Rise up, warriors of fate!
稲妻の剣で 敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemy with lightning swords!
安らぎを夢見る 鋼の勇者よ
Steel heroes who dream of peace!
守るべき未来と 愛を信じて
Believe in love and the future you must protect!
永遠へ!
To eternity!
もしも
Even if...
力尽きて 闘志の刃砕けても
our strength runs out and our blade of fighting spirit breaks,
僕らは二度と戻らない
we will never turn back.
ともに銀河の海に散ろう
Let us perish together in the sea of the galaxy.
恐れるな
Do not fear,
誇りを捨てるな
do not throw away your pride!
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
さぁ 迷わず行くんだ!
Now, move forward without hesitation!
(WO WOH WOH)
GONG 鳴らせ!!
Sound the GONG!!
雄々しく舞い踊れ 運命の戦士よ
Bravely dance, warriors of fate!
金色の翼で 天に羽ばたけ
Soar to the heavens on golden wings!
退くことを知らない 鋼の勇者よ
Steel heroes who know no retreat!
燃えたぎるソウルの 命ずるままに
As your burning soul commands!
永遠へ!
To eternity!
(WO WOH WOH)
GONG GONG GONG 鳴らせ!!
Gong, gong, sound the GONG!!
今こそ 立ち上がれ 運命の戦士よ
Now is the time! Rise up, warriors of fate!
稲妻の剣で 敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemy with lightning swords!
安らぎを夢見る 鋼の勇者よ
Steel heroes who dream of peace!
守るべき未来と 愛を信じて
Believe in love and the future you must protect!
永遠へ!
To eternity!
君は聴こえる？
Can you hear it?
僕のこの声が
This voice of mine
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
Was emptily sucked into the darkness
もしも世界が 意味を持つなら
If the world has meaning,
こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない？
Are these feelings not in vain?
憧れに押しつぶされて あきらめてたんだ
Crushed by longing, I had given up,
果てしない空の色も 知らないで
Without even knowing the color of the endless sky.
走り出した 想いが今でも
I started running, and these feelings, even now,
この胸を確かに 叩いてるから
Are definitely pounding in my chest.
今日の僕が その先に続く
The me of today continues beyond,
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
Building our own tomorrow.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer, yes, is always right here.
過ぎた季節を 嘆く暇はない
There's no time to mourn the seasons that have passed,
二度と迷って しまわぬように
So that I'll never lose my way again.
数えきれない ほんのささやかな そんな後悔 抱えたまま
Holding onto countless, tiny regrets like that,
その背中だけ追いかけて ここまで来たんだ
Chasing only after your back, I've come this far.
探していた 僕だけにできること
Searching for what only I can do.
あの日くれた 言葉が今でも
The words you gave me that day, even now,
この胸に確かに 届いているから
Definitely reach my heart.
昨日よりも 今日僕は僕の
Today, more than yesterday,
生まれてきた理由に気付いていく
I'm realizing the reason I was born.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer, yes, is always right here.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ライブ楽しいねー！
Concerts are so much fun!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！もういっちょ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! One more time!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
全てがまるで
Everything was as if
当たり前みたいだった
It was completely taken for granted.
尊い日々は まだ終わらない
Those precious days aren't over yet,
そしてまた
And then again...
走り出した 想いが今でも
I started running, and these feelings, even now,
この胸を確かに 叩いてるから
Are definitely pounding in my chest.
今日の僕が その先に続く
The me of today continues beyond,
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
Building our own tomorrow.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer, yes, is always right here.
みんなー！
Everyone!
ギリギリのロボ、カッコよかったー？
Was Girigiri Robot cool?
ロボット乗って飛んじゃったよー！
I rode a robot and flew!
すごい！カッコよかったよねー！
Awesome! That was so cool, right?
いやー、この3曲はロボットの曲をテーマに
Man, these three songs were themed around robot songs,
歌って踊らせていただきましたー！
and I got to sing and dance to them!
さらにゲストもね、たくさん出演してくれて
And we had so many guests join us too,
本当にありがとう！嬉しい！
so thank you so much! I'm so happy!
はい、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
感謝です！
I'm so grateful!
あ、そういえば、この頃... この頃... みんな気づいたかなあ...
Ah, by the way, recently... Did everyone notice?
この頃最初から実はそうだったんだけど、あの小顔ローラー頑張りまして...
Well, actually right from the start, I've been working hard with a face roller...
実わわたし、小顔になったんですよ、ねえ。
To tell you the truth, Watame's face got smaller, you know?
こう見えて...
Believe it or not...
もうあれだね、「顔デカい」って言われなくなっちゃうなーみんな！
Now nobody can call me "big face" anymore!
めんごめんご！
Sorry, sorry!
そんな変わってないって言わない！言わない！ちゃんと小さくなったの！
Don't say it hasn't changed much! It really did get smaller!
あ、この後ね、メン限3Dライブも22時15分からわためチャンネルでやりますので...
Ah, after this, the members-only 3D live will be on Watame Channel from 22:15...
他の衣装のね、この小顔のわためも見てほしいなと思います。
So I hope you'll check out this small-faced Watame in other outfits too.
歌って踊りますので、ぜひ22時15分メンバーシップに入ってお待ちくだい！
I'll sing and dance, so please join the membership and wait for 22:15!
でも！まだライブも終わりではありません！
But! The live stream isn't over yet!
ここで告知があります！
I have an announcement right here!
角巻わための新曲...
Tsunomaki Watame's new song...
「ビリ」！なんと発表いたします！
"BIRI"! I'm announcing it now!
えー、この後22時からMVが投稿されて...
Um, the MV will be posted after this at 22:00...
で、楽曲配信が24時から始まります！よろしくお願いします！
And music distribution starts at 24:00! Please check it out!
えー、神田ジョンさん、シノザキアヤトさん、DECO*27さんという陣容で作った、わためのこう新しい部分だったりとか...
Um, made by a lineup including John Kanda, Ayato Shinozaki, and DECO*27, showcasing new sides of Watame...
ま、ちょっとあんまり歌ったことないような感じの曲になっているかなと思っているので、えー、ぜひ楽しみにしてて... あ、でも！
Well, it feels like a style I haven't sung much before, so please look forward to it! Ah, but!
あ、でもこの後、まだ1曲ぐらい、お、やる時間があるか... うん...
Ah, but after this, there's still time to perform about one more song... Yeah...
あ、じゃあ、「ビリ」やろうか！
Ah, then shall we perform "BIRI"?
えー、あと1曲「ビリ」、新曲、ぜひみんなに聴いていただきたいなと思うので、最後まで...
One more song, the new song "BIRI"—I'd love for everyone to hear it, so until the end...
あのダンスも可愛いんでね、ちょっと一生懸命踊ります。見てください！
The dance is also cute, so I'll dance my best. Please watch!
では、最後の曲... 聴いてください。「ビリ」。
Now, the final song... Please listen. "BIRI".
Zetto 迷子で ぐだぐだだ
"Zetto" lost and slacking off
もうハイ or ロー ガチャで ぐちゃぐちゃ更新
High or Low gacha, messy updates
合唱 ネガポジ ラララ 毎回 歌うわ なんてこったい感
Chorus of nega-posi la-la-la, singing it every time, what a shocker feeling
ぐずぐずやるだけやるしかない
Grudgingly doing only what I have to do
ちっちゃいことでへこんでらんない
Can't get down over small things
圧迫するまで下がるだけ
Just sinking until under pressure
ご心配いらずの
No need to worry
ジェットコースター
Roller coaster
研ぎ上げた脳でおめかし さぞかしハッピーでいっぱい
Dressed up with a sharpened mind, surely full of happiness
抱き込んだ願いが香り立つ 今僕になるんだ
The held-tight wish starts to fragrance, now becoming me
僕しかできないこと 認めてほしいの
Wanting recognition for what only I can do
「どうせ」とか思ってらんないわ
Can't keep thinking "anyway..."
だっせー 妄言ばこん！ 切り刻んでいこう
Lame! Delusions thwack! Let's slice them up
まだ一等賞まで 放電がありそう
Still till first prize, seems like there's discharge
当選しちゃうかは
Whether I'll win the prize
挑戦次第 オーケー やるかやれないかだ
depends on trying! OK, it's do or don't
「はぁ めんどッぽい」「これでエンドッぽい」
"Ah, seems bothersome," "Seems like the end with this"
叩き潰した弱音がちょー痛い
Crushed weak complaints super hurt
夢が叶っちゃって甘くなれ 黙れ 不完全はノー
Dreams come true so grow sweet, shut up, incomplete is NO
ノー ノー グッバイ
No no goodbye
昨今 やることやるだけバッド
Lately doing just what needs to be done feels bad
もう涙腺アミダ 全泣きが確定
Already tear duct ghost leg lottery, guaranteed full crying
同情求めて ほわほわわ ねぇ
Seeking sympathy, fluffy-fluff, hey
ちゃんと抱き留めて えっとえっと...
Hold me tight, um, um...
顔出した絶望で ごまかし乗る歌詞 ハッピーが足りんない
With despair poking its head out, lyrics riding on cover-ups, lacking happiness
あたしを愛せない 比べたら 比べるだけ負け犬 (ルーザー)
Can't love myself, comparing makes me just a loser
ありなし選べちゃうけど 弱気なるかも
Can choose yes or no, but might lose confidence
「どうせ無理」思って仕舞っちゃうわ
Thinking "it's impossible anyway" and putting it away
だっせー 有言だもん！ 叶わないもん！
Lame! Talked the talk! Won't come true!
また一等賞 指くわえて見てるの
Watching first place again with finger in mouth
あたしじゃない 誰かだったの
Wasn't me, it was someone else
ノーノー 誰か倒れてよ
No no, someone fall down
せーの で段違いの未来 (いやいや無理だって)
Ready-set-go for an unprecedented future (No no impossible)
前進 もっとハイになって (あー きびしー)
Advance, get more high (Ah, tough)
息ができない
I can't breathe!
ローさん黙ってね？
Law-san, shut up, okay?
わぁわぁ全部虚勢ってバレそうになってんじゃん
Wow, wow, it's about to be exposed as all a bluff!
はいはいアツアツエスキュウブレイク！
Yeah, yeah, piping hot S-class break!
アクセル！ 噛み合わないで笑えるくらい
Accelerator! So out of sync it's almost laughable!
それならこのまま行くしかないか
Then I guess there's no choice but to keep going like this!
役割分担 それのがいいか
Division of roles, is that better?
大丈夫！ 無理無理 重ねて
It's fine! Impossible, impossible, layer it on!
僕しか会えない子と 仲良くしてるの
I'm getting along with a kid that only I can meet.
どうせならかましてみちゃいますか
Might as well pull it off and show them!
妄言ばっか切り刻んでいこう
Let's slice through all these delusions!
また一等賞 響く愛で
First place again, with resounding love!
見ててでも誰かじゃない僕がいいんだよ
Watch me, but I'm the one you want, not someone else!
オーケー 私の描く未来
Okay, the future I draw!
鳴呼突破 溢れ出せば
Ah, breakthrough! If it overflows...
こすり倒した美学で喋りたい
I want to speak with well-worn aesthetics!
夢が叶ったって止まれない 黙れ
Even if dreams come true, I can't stop! Shut up!
完全はノーノーノーノーノーノーノー
Perfection is no no no no no no no!
グッバイ
Goodbye!
美 美 美な
Bi-bi-beautiful...
みんなー！
Everyone~!
角巻わため生誕祭2025『アニソン Night Fever!』楽しんでいただけましたでしょうかー！
Did you enjoy Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Festival 2025 "Anison Night Fever!"?!
ここからは告知がありますので、もう少しお付き合いお願いします！
We have some announcements coming up next, so please stay tuned a bit longer!
まず！
First!
さっきも告知させていただきましたが、このあと10時にわためチャンネルにて、角巻わための新曲『ビリ』のMVが公開されます！
As I announced earlier, at 10:00 PM tonight, the MV for my new song "Biri" will be released on Watame Channel!
チャンネルはそのままでお願いします！
Please stay right here on the channel!
そして24時から、『ビリ』の楽曲配信も始まりますので、ぜひ3rdライブを実現させるためにも買っていただけると嬉しいです！
And starting at midnight, digital streaming for "Biri" begins, so to help make my 3rd solo live happen, please buy it!
さらに！このあと10時から、角巻わため誕生日記念2025のグッズが発売開始になります！
Plus! Starting at 10:00 PM tonight, Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2025 merch goes on sale!
フルセットはこんな感じー！なんですが、ひとつずつ紹介したいと思います！
The full set looks like this! Let me introduce each item one by one!
まず、ふーみママ描き下ろしのTシャツ！
First, a T-shirt illustrated by Fuumi-mama!
正面はポケットから出てる風の絵わためとイトがいます。
On the front, E-Watame and Ito look like they're peeking out of a pocket.
背面には「あーよ」って感じで挨拶してるわためがいるので、後ろの人から見ても楽しめるTシャツとなっております！
On the back, Watame is greeting with a "Hey there!", so anyone behind you can enjoy it too!
そして、わためいとジャージ！わための制服衣装とお揃い色違いの黄色いジャージになってまして、背面にはわためが描き下ろしたわためいとエアギターがプリントされておりますー！
Next, the Watamate Track Jacket! It's a yellow jacket matching my school uniform, featuring an air-guitar Watamate drawn by me on the back!
さらに、ぬいぐるみキーホルダー制服ジャージ衣装ver.！これがもうめちゃくちゃ可愛いー！お出かけにも連れて行きやすいサイズのぬいぐるみです！ぜひいろんなところに連れて行って羽ばたいてくださいー！
Next, the Plushie Keychain (School Uniform Track Jacket Ver.)! It's super cute and easy to take on outings! Take it with you everywhere!
そしてラストー！MACCO先生描き下ろしの缶バッジ4種セット！どのわためも可愛いので、ぜひ痛バッグなどに使ってください！
And lastly~! A set of 4 button badges by MACCO-sensei! Every Watame is cute, so put them on your ita-bags!
こちらのフルセットをご購入いただいた方には、角巻わためのショートボイスセットとチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
Purchasing the full set includes Tsunomaki Watame's short voice set and a Cheki-style bromide card!
ボイスはなんとー、15種類！
The voice set has 15 different types!
チェキ風ブロマイドカードには、直筆サイン＆メッセージを購入した方全員に書かせていただきます！
I will handwrite an authentic signature & message on the Cheki card for EVERYONE who buys it!
さらに、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、去年から発売された「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」で使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
Plus, as a bonus, you'll get 1 card usable in the "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME"!
このカードは、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となります。特典につくのは、推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードです！
This card is exclusive to purchases on the Official Shop. It's an Oshi Holomen card to show off your fave!
カードの詳細や遊び方については、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEの公式ホームページにてご確認ください！
For details and rules, check out the official hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME website!
とっても盛りだくさんな最強グッズなので、ぜひたくさん買っていただけると嬉しいです！
It's an ultimate line-up packed with awesome items, so I'd love it if you got them!
そして！このあと22時15分からは、メン限3Dライブがありますので、『ビリ』のMVを見て、グッズをチェックして、メン限ライブもぜひ見に来てください！
Also! A members-only 3D live starts at 10:15 PM tonight, so watch the "Biri" MV, check the merch, and come join the live!
メン限ライブでは、温度差で風邪をひく可能性が...
During the members live, the sudden mood shift might give you temperature shock...
みんなのこと待ってるねー！
I'll be waiting for you all~!
「アニソンNight Fever!!」角巻わため生誕祭2025 メンバーシップ限定アンコールライブ!!
[Anison Night Fever!! Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Fest 2025 - Membership-Only Encore Live!!]